

Nassim El Khantour

Multimedia Designer :: Art Director :: Developer

I am a French creative with an expertise in Web and Motion Design, but also proficiencies in development, 3D design, and illustration.

An extended skill set I put at work in various projects for the past 5 years such as music videos, web apps, as well as audiovisual interactive setups.

Montréal, Canada

(+33) 6 35 17 69 16

nasselkh

■ nassim.elkhantour@gmail.com

elkhantour.com

in linkedin.com/in/nassimelkhantour

Bē behance.net/elkhantour

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



Web, Print & Motion Designer

Design of visual and interactive content going from websites to motion design assets.

- Production of motion design materials and sound design (google, meta, tiktoks ads, remarketing, as well as product showcases...)
- Design of websites and print assets
- Branding/ visual identity design
- Videography and photo editing of the agency's events and venues
- Providing web developers JS libraries to improve websites user experience (3D WebGL interactive content, SVG/CSS/GSAP animations...)
- Setup and development of web apps and Adobe Extensions to enhance the agency workflow

Redbox Media Inc. Montréal, Canada 2022 - Present



💦 Freelance in Web Design & Audiovisual

- Development and Web Design of an e-commerce coupled with a dedicated SQL client for products management
- Development and UX/UI design of a web browser extension to improve Mandarin learning
- Development and UX/UI design of a website archiving various cinematographic content (MERN stack)
- Art direction, background painting and animation for an animated short-movie (music video)

Freelance Strasbourg, France 2020 - 2021

NEK Graphic & Multimedia designer

Providing visuals for various cultural structures such as associations, music acts and soundsystems.

- Spatial organisation and scenography of various videomapping installations
- Art direction and animation for an animated short-movie (music video)
- 3D modelling, animation and compositing of more than a 100 visual samples made to be projected during events
- Development and UI design of interactive audio-visual software (motion design, generative art)

Independent contractor Nancy, France 2016 - 2020

EDUCATION

DNSEP with summa cum laude

Master's degree in Digital Art

ENSAD (École Nationale Supérieure d'Art et de Design) 2019 - 2020 :: Nancy, France



Web/Game Design, Illustration, 3D Animation

International exchange program

IUP (Indiana University of Pennsylvania) 2018 - 2019 :: Indiana (PA), USA

DNA (National Diploma of Art) with honors

Bachelor's degree in Digital Art

ENSAD (École Nationale Supérieure d'Art et de Design) 2015 - 2018 :: Nancy, France

LANGUAGES

French (native)

English (fluent)

Mandarin (intermediate)

German (basic)

TECHNICALS

Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, Figma, XD, After Effects, InDesign, Audition, Logic Pro X

HTML, CSS, JS, Python, SQL (basic), PHP, C# (basic)

Maya, ZBrush, Blender, Substance Painter, Unity

TouchDesigner, Resolume Arena, MaxMSP

COMMUNITY SERVICE

mm Montrez-moi vos muscles Record

Member and visual Artist at the music record Montrez-moi vos muscles (VJ, music video)

2019 - 2021 :: Strasbourg, France

WIUP radio station

Member of the Music Team, selecting musics and helping the Web Team

2018 - 2019 :: Indiana (PA), USA

HUMMUß GAFFER

Visual research and experimentation duo with Clémence Fontaine

2016 - 2018 :: Nancy, France

ENSAD's BDE (student office)

Communication manager, designing events' communication medias

2016 - 2017 :: Nancy, France

PRESS & CURATED WORK

PHILIP PENTACLE – ANIMAL CHAMBER APOCALYPSE BEAT [OCTOBER TONE]

2021 :: Fedelab.fr

Un nouveau clip très animé pour Philip Pentacle

April 19th, 2021 :: Lalsace.fr

[NOUVEAUTÉ] PHILIP PENTACLE – ANIMAL CHAMBER APOCALYPSE BEAT

March 3rd, 2021 :: Mesenceintesfontdefaut.com

Les clips de la semaine #39

December 14th, 2020 :: Phenixwebtv.com

PERFORMANCES & EXHIBITIONS

(SELECTION)

Maison Mimir fête ses 10 ans, with Philip Pentacle and

Epic Schmetterling

March 3rd, 2020 :: MOLODOÏ, Strasbourg, France

ART'ung Live, with Philip pentacle, Noyus and

Epic Schmetterling

February 15th, 2020 :: Local ART'ung, Willerhoff, France

CELEBRATION, with Epic Schmetterling

December 5th, 2019 :: ENSAD, Nancy, France

Limedia Party #1, as part of the **RING** festival, with **CTL!** soundsystem

April 14th, 2018 :: **Théatre de la Manufacture**, Nancy, France

TECHNO, with ENSAD (BDE)

February 22nd, 2018 :: LNVRS club, Nancy, France

CTL PARTY!, with CTL! soundsystem

November 4th, 2017 :: Ostra club, Nancy, France

Ph pas neutre: Jaquarius, with CTL! soundsystem

October 6th, 2017 :: LNVRS club, Nancy, France

Festival Moumouth Fest, with Epic Schmetterling

May $7^{\text{th}}, 2017$:: Tanneries, Dijon, France

ARK4-Artem, with LATITUDES 5.4

Januray 19th, 2017 :: CCAM, Vandoeuvre-les-Nancy, France

Freshmen homecoming, with ENSAD (BDE)

December 8th, 2016 :: **Appart club**, Nancy, France

RELATED SKILLS

Illustration — Visual development — Web design Concept art — Motion graphic — Photography Video compositing — Video editing — Sound design